THE LAST DAY
Pardon me?
Got a cigarette?
Sure.
I forgot mine.
Thanks.
Well...
goodnight.
Goodnight.
Seems to be lifting,
could've eaten outside.
- It's freezing.
- Thinks it's July.
Simon called.
What time?
About 9:30.
Could've told me.
I am telling you.
Mister was awake, so he called.
That phone in the corridor's a pain.
I've said that for years.
- When does he arrive?
- Doesn't know.
Today, tomorrow. The usual mystery.
- He has work to do.
- Like to see it.
So would I.
Try his studio.
It's full of roaches.
Thanks.
- Ever seen his work?
- Call that work?
I call it hot air, not a livelihood.
Never begs from you.
No, like yourself, he'd die first.
Don't start again.
Think I'm a fool?
I know you're paying his way,
when he could easily get a job.
But I'm too dumb
to understand his "work".
You don't understand because
you won't try to.
You won't suffer, so you do nothing.
Your plates...
In we go...
Come along.
Leave your stuff, I'll prepare the room.
Sleeping in the same room?
I dunno.
Well, work it out.
Hungry?
Yes.
You sleep naked or in a T-shirt?
In a T-shirt.
What's that smell?
I love it, it's so evocative.
Maybe the wood.
Can you help?
Who's that in the photo?
- Which one?
- The big one.
- Me.
- The state of you!
The hair and all...
- My Jim Morrison look.
- A bit off!
Gonna help?
Who's he? Is that you?
No, that's...
my brother.
He died before I was born.
Careful, it's hot!
- Garlic?
- I knew you were coming.
Not true.
- Says who?
- She was waiting by the phone.
Not at all.
Maybe I call every day unknown to you.
- Off we go!
- Alice...
He calls on the sly, he ghosts around,
travels by UFO, and may be
a real-estate king!
Sorry, I don't feel well.
What's up? Can I get you something?
An anxiety attack.
I think I'll turn in.
See you tomorrow.
- It's delicious.
- Not overdone?
It's missing something.
Yes, a bit bland...
Ever the kind word.
Never know who we might hurt.
- Or be hurt by.
- Meaning who?
- Feel under attack?
- Not at all.
You don't show it.
- A madhouse.
- Simon told me.
What are you studying?
Studying? Like Simon.
Meaning?
Exactly the same thing.
Not exactly. In first year
you don't do natural drawing.
What's life drawing?
You have to draw a model
who poses on a podium...
for 10, 15, 30 minutes...
sometimes just 10 seconds
to capture the...
- And who poses?
- Who poses?
It depends... Kind of odd-looking girls,
not too pretty, kind of plump.
A bit like you, in fact.
You could do it, hear it pays well.
I met Mathieu the other day.
Told him I was coming?
Of course.
Is this clean or dirty?
Let's see.
- Clean.
- You sure?
Yeah. Leave it, I'll do it.
Fuck!
What's up?
Dammit!
Fucking thing!
I rinsed in cold water.
- How old are you?
- 17. And you?
- 18.
- Wouldn't think it.
Got some underwear?
I can't wear these for ever.
Simon!
Ask your sister to go along.
- Want to come?
- Where?
- To the pub.
- To do what?
To do what...
To dance, have a laugh,
fool around, get drunk, snort coke...
- You're off your tree.
- Well, have fun.
Can you wait a sec? I want to pee.
Keep an eye.
Thanks.
- Got a Kleenex?
- No.
Wait here, I won't be long.
Are you kidding me?
I've been waiting half an hour.
This is Mathieu...
Louise.
Hello.
Can we go? I'm sick of this.
Coming for a walk?
I dunno.
A bit of sea air...
Do you good, you're so pale.
Have I a spot there?
Looks like a spider bite.
All across your shoulders!
Hold on.
What're you doing?
It stings, but it'll cure it.
Where's my raincoat?
In the barn.
Will she ever learn to shut a door?
And he to shut his mouth?
Where are you going?
To join Dad on the boat.
What boat?
Your Dad and Gérard bought a boat.
They already decided last year.
Now it's done.
- He never told me.
- You've just arrived.
Seen the mood he's in?
That's how he is.
He's not like that with everyone.
With Alice, it's different...
Yeah, so maybe if I attempted suicide...
Simon, don't start!
I'm not starting.
You've got your Mommy.
Your darling Mommy.
Lay off, Mom, I'm 20 years old.
18.
Same thing.
Same thing...
Until we have kids,
parents just don't get it.
Where are you now?
The bar?
End of the corridor.
Le Grand Large Hotel.
Marc...
Marie...
No kiss?
Have a seat.
- Didn't think you'd come.
- Nor I.
Whisky?
No. Yes...
- How do you find me?
- Changed.
A lot or a little?
I don't know...
You haven't really changed.
I want you in my arms.
It's true.
Silly fool.
I mean it.
So?
- What, so?
- What's going on?
Nothing. Nothing special.
No...
You pop up after 20 years
and all is normal.
You thought we'd just fuck?
I didn't think anything...
All and nothing.
You speak like you write, well.
So they say...
I just felt like seeing you,
for a little while, just like that.
For no reason?
Sit down.
We can't see each other, ever again.
I have to go.
Don't ever call my place.
I'll call you.
You okay?
Fine.
I'll take a shower.
By the way...
I bumped into Mathieu.
At Chassiron...
He's teaching me to ride.
Neat, eh?
Yeah.
Any plans for tonight?
Because... Mathieu asked us round
to the lighthouse.
Want to?
No, you go ahead.
I won't go without you.
I don't feel like going out.
Now we all kiss!
Now you two!
You can do better! A big French kiss!
Come on!
Bravo!
- Where are you going?
- With Bérénice.
Her folks rented a villa in Biarritz.
You're so lucky!
Yeah, they invited me,
as a birthday gift.
Some gift.
Not something you'd know about.
No, I frequent the wrong people.
My friends are broke, their parents too.
But they're great fun,
that's their gift to me.
Imagine if you'd have to say thank you.
Wise up, will you?
Holidaying with folks
always has its price.
Not at all.
Sure, last summer you said
what a bore her mother was.
Unlike some, I like to please,
not just myself!
To please?
So you suck off her father on the sly?
That's enough!
Saw an article last year
on your exhibition.
I was real proud.
There were two photos you'd done.
But badly printed, all blurred.
They'd framed one across the forehead.
A kid at an airport, I think.
Don't you find something's changed?
Where?
Between us.
It's odd seeing you again.
Why?
Here, under these conditions.
I mean, with Louise and stuff.
What's odd about it?
It's not like before.
A dead gull on the
balcony, it's all yucky.
What's going on?
I had a nightmare.
Really?
We were on this beach...
No, don't tell.
And it's so hot, with this T-shirt...
Not hot, you?
What's up?
I've a crick in my neck.
Like a massage?
Yeah.
Where are your parents?
In Paris.
What do they do?
They get by...
My father writes, books and stuff.
And my mother left a long time ago...
upped and left, overnight.
Without saying?
Saying what?
Why don't we make love?
You prefer Mathieu, is that it?
Not in bed?
What're you doing?
Taking a bath.
- At two in the morning.
- Half-three.
Who was there?
Everyone, except you.
Martine's going to La Rochelle tomorrow.
If you want to go, she's leaving at 11.
No way.
- Sorry?
- Nothing.
Who won?
England, three nil.
Could do with a TV here.
- Thanks!
- What? Sorry.
Who wants a hot chocolate?
It's nothing...
Nothing? Like to see you.
You're pressing too hard. Let me try...
Got a bandage?
Yeah.
Really suits you.
Have a look.
How does it feel?
Isn't it a bit bridal?
No, it never really was.
It's nice and airy.
But not exactly Christmas.
That's the whole point.
Don't like Christmas?
Know anyone who does?
What's this dress?
Don't like it?
Looks like a wedding dress.
Your mother gave it to me.
Said we've got to dress up.
Look at me.
Close your eyes.
Okay.
Hurry up, they're ready downstairs.
The guests have arrived.
I need a little room...
They're here, but they don't go out.
He's okay, but she's not well.
She had breast cancer.
Really? I didn't know.
They removed the right breast.
Dear friends, I propose
a toast to our new boat.
A happy New Year to you all!
Happy New Year!
And to the future
young married couple!
What are you making?
Vodka and apple.
Is it a nice mix?
- A new cocktail?
- Taste.
It's strong.
Let me try again.
Not bad.
Want it?
Damn!
Broke my lipstick.
Can I taste too?
Smells like piss.
Show me.
It really suits you.
Should wear it more often.
Let's see again.
Thought you weren't coming.
I changed my mind.
Good.
Hi. Three beers, please.
Is it a problem that I...
get on well with her?
You sure?
I wouldn't want to...
Don't worry.
You know she's underage?
Not that it'd bother you.
On the contrary, no?
Thanks.
Doesn't suit you at all.
What?
All that gaudy make-up.
I prefer you natural, without it.
And those jingly bracelets
aren't too nice either.
They look tarty.
I think your eyes are wonderful,
as if lit from within.
Like a Breton lighthouse.
How about a last drink?
If you like... but I'm going to bed.
Me too.
Wait.
Can I have a cigarette?
I'll stay here a while.
Mom...
What time is it?
What're you doing here?
I wanted some air and I dozed off.
Did you have fun?
Goodnight.
We said never again.
You said never again.
I said never again.
Feel guilty?
I would, if I were you.
And you feel no guilt?
I wish I'd never met you.
I know.
Why really did you return?
For you.
Liar.
You want to see him.
To get to know him, is that it?
Yes.
I'm not the only one.
- Where'd you meet Simon?
- In school.
Have to buy before you eat.
2 kilos of grapes.
Right away, Madam.
Been together long?
But we're not together.
Not together?
No, we're kind of friends...
Like brother and sister?
Will that be all?
But you sleep together.
Yes, but we're not together.
Fancy some clementines?
Ripe, or not?
How much?
Half?
There you go...
10 euros, bag included.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
Goodbye.
Where's my black polo shirt?
- In the cupboard.
- I just looked.
Then, I don't know.
Wherever you left it.
Are you taking the piss?
What's wrong?
Are you crazy?
What're you doing?
See for yourself.
What's all this carry on?
I'm stifling...
Or I'm bored, if you prefer.
Where are you going?
Suddenly interested?
I'm going for a stroll,
along the harbour.
Don't you ever do that?
Alone, at this hour, no.
You're missing something.
Maybe, but if you keep...
Shut up! I'm dead tired of you!
You don't even know why you came.
Why are you here?
- Let's swim.
- Don't be stupid.
I said, let's swim.
You're crazy, I have to go.
What time is it?
Marc, what time is it?
Marc, stop!
Answer, you scare me.
Marc!
Marie!
You should've told him.
The truth,
from the very start.
But I'm not letting you go.
See? I'm holding
on and I won't let go.
Your mom's buggered off...
Don't know what's needling her.
Always at a loose end, happy nowhere...
I don't know.
Must be the mid-life crisis.
You okay?
Yeah, okay.
You haven't seen the boat yet.
Tomorrow, if you want...
And where's your fiancée?
My fiancée?
Louise.
She's gone out.
Without you?
Yeah.
I'm gonna get some sleep.
Will I leave the door ajar?
No, you can close it.
Goodnight, son.
Simon!
Where were you? We looked all over.
I'm talking to you.
He bores you without me around, eh?
Think I don't notice?
I'm going, Simon.
With Mathieu...
North of Brittany, to Ile de Houat.
I think I'm in love.
And him?
Him too.
He'll come to Paris, which proves...
Which proves you're totally naive.
It proves nothing at all.
I love you, Simon.
You wait till you leave to say it?
You love people on the way out?
We can't love as we like...
but differently.
Yeah, sure.
I left my address and
phone number in the drawer.
Just go.
Maybe we ought to leave tonight.
One day more or less...
Why?
It's more quiet on the road.
We need time to pack...
It won't take long.
I think Simon wants to stay
another week.
Leave the boat in the harbour,
come back for the weekend.
As you like...
When your brother died,
your sister was two.
I wanted another child,
another boy...
Not to replace him, Simon...
You never did take
the place of the dead.
It was to live...
to go on with life.
But your dad didn't want.
So...
I found one who did.
He leaves Saturday from
the Grand Large Hotel.
If you want to see him,
his name's Bromberg.
Marc...
Bromberg.
That door needs repainting.
- Good day.
I'd like to see Mr Bromberg...
Mister..?
Bromberg, B-R-O-M-B-E-R-G.
Sorry, he checked out this morning.
Really?
Thank you.
Sorry, it's me again.
What room was he in?
I'll just check for you...
Room 112.
Thank you.
Am I dead?
Have I died or not?
I don't care...
Even if I am dead I'll return,
next year...
with my Mommy.
We'll go for a drive and sing songs.
Subtitles by Peter Leonard
Processed by L.V.T. - Paris
Corrections of timings
and OCR errors: SmallBrother