Provides explosiveskull https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
[UKULELE MUSIC GAMES ON THE RADIO] Saving subtitle as a Draft!
[WOMEN'S SCREAMS]aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaasdsadsa
Hang on! Do not! [SHE SMILES]
[UKULELE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[WOMEN'S SCREAMS]
[LAUGH]
[WOMAN]: Hey, I told you to stop that!
Oh, yes, because I'm listening to you.
What do we think of this place?
Yes, I like this place.
That? Do you think we could stay here?
Maybe.
The tide is moving. We better get back.
- [CAMERA CLICKS] - Good for the blog.
[SHE BRICKS]
[SHE PARK]
Oh my God. There was something here.
There was something there!
- Nothing there. - There's something there!
I do not see anything. There is nothing here.
[SHE SHOUTS]
- There was something there! - Honey, there's nothing there.
I literally just saw something!
Tracy! Trag!
- Calm down. I trust you, okay? - ALRIGHT.
- I believe you. - ALRIGHT.
- Let's go back, okay? - ALRIGHT. ALRIGHT.
Nice and quiet, okay? Come on.
[LUKE]: Come on, baby.
[TRACY]: Luke, pozuri!
[LUKE]: Oh, fuck.
Luke?
Luke!
No no no!
- [Screams] - No!
Born!
[ONA SOBS]
[SHE SHOUTS]
[PTICE WARBLE]
[BIRDS SQUAWK]
Fucking great!
[GIRL]: Ugh.
If you wanted a slide
we could have gone to Dreamworld.
Charlie.
There were only a few turns.
- And a chandelier. - Ah, shit.
You must be kidding. Why?
You know what, your mess, clean it up.
Alright?
Well, technically, it wasn't my mess.
Hey, I thought you were a nurse.
Nurse, Charlie. Triage.
Urine bottles and vomit bags are not on my radar.
[ON ZASJEČE]
He vomited on the microphone.
Well, don't put it there!
Bathroom. Come on.
I'll have to change the plugs soon.
He starts to run a little rough at idle.
ALRIGHT. AND?
I think that's enough work for today.
You know, there are a few beers out there
with our names on them.
You know I'm mad at you, don't you?
It doesn't look like that.
[ON SE SMEKA]
Well ...
the bank called again today.
Mm.
I told them you would call them
when you landed.
[HE IS LEAVING]
Come on.
Want me to charm them in an extra few weeks?
Yeah, well, I'd love that
but we cannot do that forever.
I can.
We can not.
If we do, they will terminate our credit line
and then we can’t run the business.
Sometimes you can be so damn practical.
Okay, you won.
I'll call them.
Thank you.
What?
Nothing.
Do you ever think we should get married?
[TELEPHONE BUZZING]
Keep that thought.
Pearl Air Charter usluga.
-That. Yes, we do.
I just need to check my ... my reservations
but when did you think?
OK, great. I can ... I can do it.
Have you been to the site?
Super.
Super. ALRIGHT.
Just give me your email address.
Gives.
Perfect. Well, I'll throw you a note to confirm
and see you tomorrow.
- Tomorrow? - Yes!
Hell's ridge. Lunch on the ridge. The whole enchilada!
- Tomorrow? - Yes, noon.
- Hello.
It's OK. This is good.
[BIRDS SQUAWK]
Hey! They are here.
- It's a nice car. - Fancy.
All right, let's go.
"Minaza." I thought he was Italian.
[KAZ]: Hi, there.
Kaz Fellows.
Welcome to the Pearl Coast, Mr. Minas.
Yoji, but everyone calls me "Jo."
Thank you. My wife, Michelle.
- Hello. - Hello. This is Charlie.
You two talked on the phone yesterday.
[JO]: Ah, yes, of course. Captain Charlie.
"CC." Kao cips.
- Yes. - I'm glad to meet you.
- And you. - Uh, are we ready?
We are ready. You are ready.
- [JO]: Very good. - Great.
[JO]: I told you we'd do the 12th in a row.
If you are interested, there is a wonderful scuba dive.
Oh, I like it. Family races.
But we don't get much water.
Not. I'll just sit on the beach
and if I have a cold beer in my hand, I will be happy.
Now I can guarantee it.
Alright. Well, come on. I'll show you the circle.
[MICHELLE]: Oh, wonderful.
[KAZ]: We're just loading everything.
- Watch your step here. - Oh thank you.
- Oh. - Oh.
- You first. - [SHE LAUGHS]
- [CHARLIE]: Let's go, shall we? - Yes.
Um, how long?
[CHARLIE]: 90 minutes cruise. Arrive in time for a late lunch.
Great.
I hope you don’t expect anything too harsh?
I'm not a good flyer.
I make sure all my passengers have a good flight.
Is he coming?
Benny is our chef.
As long as that's all he does.
[BATHING]
[CAMERA CLICKS]
Are you okay there?
Yes, we are.
Keep your eyes open, you could see the whale.
Or a shark.
- Shark? - Great white.
You don't want to go swimming with one of them, do you, Jo?
Benny.
[CHARLIE]: Unlikely.
It's the wrong time of year.
- Are you sure? - Oh yes.
He's safe.
Charlie trained as a marine biologist here.
He was good.
I thought so too
until the shark bit me.
Go.
- Really? What happened? - Darling, please.
Maybe he doesn't want to talk about it, you know.
Bring back bad memories.
No, no, it's okay. I don't care.
I explored reef sharks with a black tip
and their pack hunting skills.
They're damn good at it.
One day I went out alone, the first mistake
and one grabbed me from behind and spat.
I never saw him come.
Another mistake, not paying attention.
Luckily, it was more of a love bite than a real chomp.
A love bite that kept him in the hospital for two weeks.
Ooh, you're going to love this, Joji.
Hey, a few years ago, a group of tourists
went on one of the shark tours ...
[ANIMATES TOPIC FROM "JELLY"]
... when the three-meter shark is a bright white
jumped into the back of the boat ...
[VRAŠTA] He scared the hell out of them.
Benny.
It's OK.
Welcome to Hell's Reef.
We did it.
Sluzbeno se zove "Imperious Reef"
but local divers renamed it
after a pearl was wrecked here on the reef
there during a storm.
It’s actually a crazy story.
Eight crew members were blocked here for 15 days
without food and water.
Only one of them survived, ...
An eighteen-year-old Japanese diver.
Saeki Morita.
-Gives.
My grandpa.
[BENNY]: October 12, 1951.
Do you know the story?
Every pearl knows a story.
Saeki is a bit of a legend here.
His death wish was to be here with his colleagues from the ship.
Shall we look around?
- Uh ... - Yes, yes.
- Go, go. Here. - Oh. Thank you.
You will tell them it is a national park
and that shouldn't work?
No I did not.
Just go help Benny, okay?
[BENNY]: Come on, big boy.
[CHARLIE]: Amazing.
I love it here.
[KAZ]: Me too.
Hey, you know how we were, um
yesterday he talked crazy
about the idea of ​​maybe getting married?
I think you should make me an honest man.
[SHE BRICKS]
Well, I don't know if that's possible
- but if you were shit ... - Look!
God, they're beautiful.
Charlie?
Mm?
I am pregnant.
Vau.
-Gives.
Wow!
Will you say something else?
Woof! Are you ... are you okay?
I'm fine.
Is that it?
So, what now?
I think we, uh ...
complete this journey and then ...
get married, yes?
Are you sure?
About pregnancy or marriage?
No, about me being a father.
[SHE LAUGHS] What a jerk you are.
I know this is ...
it was not planned at all
but are you okay
It's me.
I really did.
It’s a surprise, but great.
I just don't know what we're going to do, you know?
With work and money, we and the baby ...
We'll be fine.
More than fine.
We'll break it. As always.
[BENNY]: Hey!
- Charlie! - What is he doing?
Kaz!
What's up, buddy?
You two have to come with me.
Hi, Michelle.
Are you OK?
No, it's not fucking good.
Wow. What is?
There.
[FLY CONNECTIONS]
Charlie.
[WOMAN MORE]: Charlie!
Fuck.
Ah, shit.
We have to get them out of here, okay?
[JO]: A shark attacked him?
-Gives.
- Tell someone? - Already did.
[KAZ]: The Coast Guard will solve it.
It must be somewhere out there.
What?
Their ship.
She could still be alive.
And it won't last long out there.
She? How do you know there's someone else?
We should leave this to the authorities.
You have no idea where to look
and the chance of finding something is almost zero.
- Yes, we have to try. - I want to get out of here.
- My charter, my call! - That's not happening, buddy.
[ONA ZDIHA]
[ENGINE YELLOW LEVEL]
We have a 45-minute fuel reserve
so we'll take a look at this place.
We'll be at 1000 feet.
If anyone sees anything, we'll check.
I guess all this shit failed yesterday
so with the tides
the best we can do is cover the east side.
There! Down!
OK, let's go down.
I have to look.
-Gives.
Born.
You can not.
If you get hurt down there, who's flying this plane?
Benny?
Of course.
If something goes wrong, bang on the hull.
Loud.
[MOVEMENT PLANNING]
Come on, Benny.
[HEAVY FUCKING]
[BENNY SHOUTS]
[INTERESTED]
Benny!
[BREATHING HARD]
Are you OK?
Was she attacked?
Shit.
[KAZ]: Come on, guys.
Let's get out of here.
Are you OK?
What's next?
Judgment.
Come on, Benny, move.
[BENNY]: Yes. Sweet as.
[SHE IS VERY]
[LOUD RUMBLE]
[CHARLIE]: What was that?
Michelle. Hi! Hey Hey hey.
- Are you OK? - Uh ...
- Get her out of here! - [JO]: Come on!
Benny! Where's Benny?
- Benny! - I can't take off!
- Wow! - Benny, get a life raft.
OFFICE OFFICE. Move. Were done.
This thing will be at the bottom in a few minutes.
- Take the belt. - I can not ...
ALRIGHT. Are you OK?
- Are you sure? - Now, Jo!
I warned you. I told you.
- Get out! - [MICHELLE]: Come on, Jo.
[CHARLIE]: Mayday, mayday, mayday!
- Hidroavion Cessna 206 ... - Charlie!
We have to get out of here!
Just grab everything you can. Life jackets, torches, suits
water, however.
May day! May day! May day! Cessna 206 seaplane, 31417.
15 nautical miles northeast of Hell's Reef.
[RADIO SOUNDS] Can you hear me? Please answer.
Charlie, we need to get out now!
Five POBs, right pontoon destroyed.
We are sinking fast.
If you read me, please answer! Done!
[RADIO HISSES]
- Get on the raft, Jo! - I'm not getting into it!
Anyway, but this plane is
I'll be at the bottom in a minute.
I don’t float around with that stuff over there!
Yeah, please!
Like I said, your choice.
- Put on a life jacket! - Yeah!
[METAL MOVEMENTS]
Yeah, come on!
[BENNY]: Pozuri!
Already!
- [MICHELLE]: Hajde, Jo! - [JO GRUNTS]
That! Quickly!
[KAZ]: Come on!
Quickly! Get him!
[BENNY PANTS]
[METAL MOVEMENTS]
[LOUD RUMBLE]
[VAZDI]
[BENNY GROANS]
You will need a few stitches
but it’s not really that deep.
Sorry.
Thanks, Kaz.
Did you go out on a day off?
Maybe, I'm not sure.
Country se.
He's not sure.
That shit has a safety signal?
He left by plane.
We are under attack.
We float around in this piece of plastic trash
and you’re not sure if anyone knows how fucked up we are
or even where are we?
What about the lifeboat?
He's on his way, isn't he?
Shouldn't we wait for them? They know we're here.
[BENNY]: We're on.
We'll be 75 hp from here by morning.
It will take them days to find us.
And the search plane?
It will be dark soon.
He won't send a plane to the first light.
We are far from the course
and I understand 150,000 from the coast ...
150 kilometers?
Our best chance is to use electricity.
He runs for us even if we row with him
we could land by tomorrow afternoon.
If they don't pick us up before then.
Can we go back? To the ridge?
Not an option.
You say.
-Gives.
And what do you have to say, my friend?
Because everything I've seen so far
is a bunch of writing and moaning.
What, do you have a better idea?
The current runs on five nodes.
Running east, towards the coast.
Hell's Reef is there, in the southwest.
We can't paddle, we won't get anywhere.
So we use it to get to shore.
They are facts, you are an analyst.
you fucking understand that.
About what...
to?
Maybe it will disappear.
Maybe rising temperatures have ruined their season.
Maybe a lack of fish.
So far so good.
[VAZDI]
Have you seen?
I?
About five meters.
Still, at home I saw the evening.
How's the hand?
I can row.
- [KAZ]: Are you okay? - Yes.
You'll have a little bump there
but it's not really that bad.
Thanks.
- I'll survive. - [BATHING]
Jo hates water.
It always is.
He almost drowned when he was a child.
I had to work on it
just to get him to come on this trip.
And this is happening.
-Gives.
How did you meet Charlie?
Uh, what am I ...
I worked at the hospital
when he was brought in after the attack.
I was actually amazed at how calm he was.
Although he almost lost his leg.
That's Charlie for you.
Do you have any children?
No way.
I mean, I'm ...
I'm just not ready yet.
I see.
Somehow I feel the same.
Are you...
-Gives.
When should you arrive?
In about seven months.
[WIND TIMES]
How far do you think we have come?
Maybe 15 pcs.
That's good.
-That. Yes, we are fine.
Speak, Captain. What do you say?
I said we still have over 130 hp.
[JO]: What was that?
[BENNY]: Eto.
- There. - Shark!
Already!
Sit down, you idiot!
- Fuck off! Leave us alone. - [BENNY LAUGHS]
It's a dolphin.
Yes! Sit down.
[BENNY]: It's a dolphin.
[ON The dolphin opponent]
[CLICK DOLFINA]
Oh my God.
Fuck Jo. You scared me!
What?
What if you fell into the sea?
-Gives.
-That. You're right.
[SHRUBS]
How many more do we have?
[CHARLIE]: That's the last one.
You know sharks, don't you?
I thought I did.
And as you pointed out, I am an investment analyst.
Do you know what that means? What am I doing?
I study situations.
Weigh the prospects, and then, based on the facts
I anticipate the outcomes.
You say you're a good marine biologist.
Well, I'm a good, very good analyst.
A clinical assessment of our situation, as I see it
is if the shark is still out
I would rate our chances that we all survive on ...
less than 5%.
And that would be fucking optimistic.
So do you think it's gone?
- I really do not know. - Shit!
You said they weren't out here
and that thing is and kills people!
It's not gone.
He knows it, and she knows it.
- What do you want from me? - Fucking truth.
ALRIGHT.
He's still out there.
And it's close.
[SHRUBS]
Hey!
It is sufficient.
I can do a little more.
Give me your hands.
[SHRUBS]
Thank you.
Oh, shit.
Michelle?
I think I dropped the paddle.
What do you mean, you fell?
I was rowing and it just seemed that way
to get out of my hand. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I got it!
There!
I'm sorry. It's me...
[WOMAN]: Charlie!
Kaz! Kaz!
- No, no, no, no! - I'll be fine. I'm fine.
Come on, Kaz.
She's almost there, she's almost there.
Just there ...
Come on, Kaz, come on.
Come on, Kaz.
Kuckin sin.
Kaz! Kaz! Come on, Kaz, get away!
Come on, Kaz! Move!
Move, Kaz!
Quick!
Up, up, up!
[CUT]
[SHRUBS]
Here, put this on. They will keep you warm.
Thanks.
Here, let me help you with that ...
Get your hands off my wife!
- Back off. - What did you say?
[CHARLIE]: Hey, Benny.
I said get that stick out of your ass
and use it for rowing.
[DONIJU]
- [Benny screams] - Benny!
[KAZ]: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Benny! Benny!
- Benny ... - Where is he? Benny!
- Benny, come on! - Come on.
Benny, Benny, come on!
- Calm down. Nice. - Oh, my hand!
- [KAZ]: Come on! - Hey, look at me.
- Come on, Benny. - Come on, right here.
Right here. Look at me, Benny. Come on.
- I'm almost there. - I have you.
Come on!
Come on, we're almost there.
Give me your hand.
[CHARLIE]: Come on, buddy.
[KAZ]: Let's get you inside.
[BENNY YELLOW]
- [MICHELLE SCREAMS] - Benny! Ne!
Benny! What!
[SHRUBS]
- Fucking idiot! - Don't, don't, don't.
- Fuck you ... - Don't, don't!
It's not worth it.
Benny.
[WIND TIMES]
[SHRUB ERRORS]
I had it.
I had his hand.
If only I could keep him a little longer
- I think I could ... - Stop. Stop.
It's not your fault.
[SHRUBS]
Hi, Michelle.
Just one bite.
Thanks.
If he could get close enough ...
His brain is small, located between his eyes
in the middle of the skull
which is quite unprotected.
If this is in the right place
it could work.
You should be very close.
That's tricky.
That's a terrible idea, Charlie.
I didn’t say it was a good plan.
Please.
Vec.
Evo.
To rest.
Thank you.
- [LOUD FIGHTING] - [KRISTE]
Charlie!
Get back on the raft, everyone get off the water!
[CUT]
Already!
Move, Jo. Movement!
- Move! - Hurry up!
Yeah, no!
- Move, Jo. Movement! - Move!
That! That!
That! Swim!
[YELLOW]
Just swim! Swim to us now.
That! [MICHELLE SORRY]
[JO GROSS]
[KAZ]: Come on, let's go!
- [VRLI] - [MICHELLE KRISTI]
- [MICHELLE SCREAMS] - Yeah! Not!
Not! Not!
[ONA SOBS]
Easy. Easy. Take it easy, Michelle. Easy.
[MICHELLE SOBS]
He went.
Kaz? Hej, Kaz?
Kaz, look at me. Hey, look at me.
I'm fine!
[SHE CONCLUDES]
Jo ... Jo! Is ...
He's alive, he's alive. He's ... come on Jo!
Yes! Quickly!
Jo, Jo! Fast, fast ...
Yeah, it's okay. We'll catch him.
Please ...
Already!
Help me.
Please.
[HE SHOUTS]
Yes! Not!
Don't ... [MICHELLE SOBS]
[IN JAPANESE]: Please take care of him, Grandpa.
[THREE AND THREE]
Michelle?
Michelle.
We can't give up.
We have to keep trying.
We can still survive, okay?
Like my grandfather.
[ONA ZDIHA]
-Gives.
ALRIGHT.
[CHARLIE]: He punctured the raft.
We're losing air.
If we do nothing, we die.
But if we keep this bloody thing on the move
there is still a chance we can get home.
Why don't you both get some rest?
No, it's okay. We can continue.
Kaz, just get some rest
the current leads us in the right direction.
I'm fine.
Just give yourself a break, baby.
We're doing well.
Oh, shit.
- Charlie? - It's okay, stay calm.
If he gets close enough, I might have half a chance.
It's OK. Be calm.
[KAZ]: Where is he?
Yes ...
[THAT CRUST] Where is it?
I don't see him.
Damn it!
- Charlie, what? What? - Fuck!
Love in packs!
[YELLOW]
[COSTUME]
[ARTICLE]
[SHE IS VERY]
[KAZ VRIČI]
[ARTICLE]
I love you.
Where is?
[CHARLIE]: In the middle, in the middle.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
[SEABIRD SQUAWKS]
Coast.
I see the coast.
Oh my God. We will succeed!
[SHE LAUGHES]
Charlie!
We did it, Charlie. We succeeded!
All right, come on, let's go.
Oh, fuck.
What should we do? We are sinking.
Charlie, this raft won't make it to shore.
[WOMAN]: Charlie!
What are you doing? Charlie!
Girls, you're going to run.
Whatever happens, just don't look back.
Just get to the shore. Just get out of here.
Charlie, no. No!
Together.
We're doing this together, okay?
I should have taken care of you.
Together.
Always together.
ALRIGHT.
Right here.
You get it in your mouth or in your eye
and I go for the brain.
Take one out, and then we'll go for the other, okay?
OK, swim. Just get to the mainland.
Are you ready?
-Gives.
Come on, fucking jerks, come on!
Michelle! Swim!
Now! Swim!
Come on!
[SMELLED YELLOW]
Sad!
[TWISTED]: Now!
[COSTUME]
[MARINE BREEDING]
[SHE CONCLUDES]
[SILENT]
[KAZ]: Charlie!
Born!
Kaz!
Oh my God. Come on, come on!
[CUT]
[ARTICLE]
Where's Charlie?
[KAZ WAILS]
[GIVE AWAY]
[CHRIST]
Michelle!
Kaz!
Shit.
Michelle!
When I tell you
swim to shore as fast as you can.
You?
I'll be right behind you.
Now! Go now!
[HEAVY FUCKING]
[SHE IS VERY]
[METAL MOVEMENTS]
[MARINE BREEDING]
[BIRD WARBLE]
[ARTICLE]
[GLAZBA: "Panika" Annie Hamilton]
Provides explosiveskull https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
"I've been looking behind me for weeks."
♪ In the darkest hours ♪
"I'd leave the light on."
♪ I couldn’t see much, but you’ll see in ♪
"I was hoping you'd try to find me."
♪ I played for you, but seconds in ♪
Ste You threw me like a seagull thrown into the wind ♪
♪ And I feel like panic is setting in ♪
"I can't read your writing now."
♪ But I like how it looks ♪
"Through the pages of your books."
♪ And I hear ♪
Like a plate rotation ♪
♪ Circle the corners of my mind ♪
Like a self-portrait from the time you see in ♪
"In the darkest hours, I would leave the light on."
Cam I feel panic in ♪
[SONG CONTINUES]